ANGEL CONTRERAS SUAREZ

■ electagls@hotmail.com

+52 222 577 0468

Puebla, Mex.

SKILLS

Bash, Python, JEE app servers and webservers like Apache HTTP, Nginx, JBoss, WAS, WebLogic, IIS, IHS, OHS, Tomcat, IBM MQ, MySQL, middleware and bash/python scripting in the main. Handle GitHub, SNOW, Rundeck, IBM RTC.

Knowledge:

Docker, Kubernetes (lens, helm, kubesealed), Jenkins (ngrok, webhooks), Git, Terraform, Ansible Prometheus and Grafana. Ongoing: Terraform and K8s with AWS.

- Critical Thinking
- Problem-Solving
- Self-taught
- Diligent
- Empathy
- Collective property
- Teamwork
- Emotional Intelligence.

EDUCATION

Benemérita Universidad Autónoma de Puebla (BUAP)

Degree: Computer Science

Engineering - 2017

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native English: 90%

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Committed IT engineer with 4+ years of experience in IT Support field, mainly in Middleware and virtual servers (servers on premise and on cloud). Ambitiously aided individuals by handling Java EE Application Servers and Web Servers. Diligently assisted with automation by scripting (bash) creation in order to make work easier. Excellent at collaborating with a team on critical projects and troubleshooting analytics. Strong background on Windows, Linux, and UNIX environment working with enterprise ITIL processes and best practices of DevOps culture with their principal tools. It's easy for me to adapt to new environments, teams, and projects. My passion is everything related to the IT field and the satisfaction of solving complex problems.

WORK HISTORY

March 2022 to present. (Remote)
 HCL Technologies
 WAS Administrator

IT support for a US bank using IBM RTC and AWC for CI/CD and Rundeck to run jobs and automation. Managing instances of Websphere Application Server and JBoss, all through automated jobs and SNOW for tracking task.

 April 2018 - February 2022 Puebla - Mexico T-Systems México Middleware Engineer

Support and manage many Middleware products like JBoss, WebSphere Application Server (WAS), WebLogic Server, Apache Tomcat, Apache HTTP Server, Oracle HTTP Server, IBM HTTP Server, IBM MQ, IIS, FTP/SFTP Filezilla, Bitvise. I'm on charge of Application Servers sub-team and keeping alive the service of the applications and all the management of that, mitigate vulnerabilities, troubleshooting of issues and make the changes in the MW to get better performance. Also managing the SSL/TLS protocols and digital certificates. All the activities through the ITIL standards and using ticketing tools like Service Now, SM9 or Remedy.

January 2018 - April 2018 Puebla - Mexico

T-Systems México

IT Support

IT support for many clients applying the standards of ITIL process, the main activities were configuration (custom applications), monitoring (jira), catch and dispatch (SM9, jira), checking logs and implementing automations by scripting.

 September 2017 - January 2018 Puebla - Mexico T-Systems México (Professional Practices)

Design and develop a Chatbot with AWS and Python, which automates processes within the company, doing tasks such as maintaining a coherent conversation with the user or providing information requested instantly. This prototype was for the area of Technological Innovation practitioners.

 March - June 2016 Puebla - México Jobo Group Quality Executive

Moderate company ads for vacancies, moderate activity users of the jobomas.com, monitoring quality of the site and its content.